The Fr. Christopher K. Kandakai, 1928-2011 LCP2011/05
Liberian Collections
The Fr. Christopher K. Kandakai Collection
1928-2011
Liberian Collections
Kandakai, Christopher K.
LCP2011/05
10 cubic feet; 10 records cartons
A student of Cuttington College, Fr. Christopher K. Kandakai became an ordained Epsicopal priest in 1951. He was Liberia's longest serving Episocpal priest and served as rector and priest-in-charge of many Episcopal churches in Liberia and trained many Episcopal theologians. Additionally, Kandakai was an avid linguist who translated the New Testament into both Gola and Vai languages. This collections contains materials pertaining to the Episcopal Church as well as to adult education and linguistics. A large selection of his materials are written in Vai, only one of two African languages with an original script, unrelated to Latin or Arabic.
Access Restrictions
Closed for research.
Biographical Note
Pending
Arrangement
The Fr. Christopher K. Kandakai Collection is organized into six series:
Education
Episcopal Church
Government and Politics
Language and Linguistics
Programs and Announcements
Subject Files
.
Scope and Content
The Fr. Christopher K. Kandakai Collection spans the period from 1928-2011 and is organized into six series: Education, Episcopal Church, Government and Politics, Language and Linguistics, Programs and Announcements, and Subject Files.
The Education series contains materials from various schools and missions thoughout Liberia, including the University of Liberia and Cuttington College. Also within this series is the Adult Education subseries which contains reports and correspondence from a number of Liberian adult education associations.
The Episcopal Church series has correspondence, financial information and reports pertaining to the Episcopal Church. Also included in this collection are many religious newsletters, magazines, and newspapers. A major subseries is the Diocesan Conventions which span the years from 1954-2003.
Government and Politics includes materials from the three branches of the Liberian government as well as materials on the Constitutional Advisory Assembly.
Language and Linguistics contains reports, correspondence and other materials from different language programs in Liberia. It is within this series that all of the Vai materials are housed; this includes teaching materials, booklets and extensive manuscripts from Kandakai's bible translations.
The Programs and Announcements series is a lengthly series that includes funeral and wedding programs, Liberia Official Gazette death announcements, life sketches and other religious and non-religious programs. A complete list of individuals who have a funeral program in this collection can be obtained by contacting the staff at the Liberian Collections at Indiana University.
The Subject Files series contains miscellaneous materials that couldn't easily be housed in other series. These include non-religious newsletters and magazines, invitations, personal materials, conference materials, reports and correspondence. Fr. Kandakai was an elaborate notetaker who documented his daily musings, sermon ideas, thoughts and feelings in notebooks, on scrap paper and on any other surface he could find. All of these notes have been kept together and put into a subseries within this series. They are arranged chronologically when possible but most of the notes are undated.
Copyright Transferred
Copyright interests for this collection have been transferred to the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, contact the Indiana University Liberian Collections
Liberia; Adult education; Missions--Liberia; Vai; Kandakai, Christopher K.; American Bible Society; Cuttington College and Divinity School; Episcopal Church; Institute for Liberian Languages; Liberia. Dept. of Education; University of Liberia
- Education (Box 1)
  - Adult Education
    - African Adult Education Association,, undated, 1978 (Box 1)
    - African Adult Education Association 6th Biennial Conference,, undated, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Afrolit,, undated, 1977-1982 (Box 1)
    - International Council for Adult Education,, undated, 1978 (Box 1)
    - International Literacy Day, undated, 1973-1979 (Box 1)
    - Liberia National Adult Education Association,, undated, 1978-1982 (Box 1)
    - Liberian National Adult Education Association Conference, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous, undated, 1977-1979 (Box 1)
    - National Adult Education Association of Liberia,, undated, 1979-1995 (Box 1)
    - Reports, undated, 1975-1979 (Box 1)
    - Reports – Other African Countries, undated, 1979 (Box 1)
    - Seminar on Non-Formal Education, undated, 1978 (Box 1)
    - Women, undated (Box 1)
  - Cuttington College,, undated, 1962-1983 (Box 1)
  - Julia C. Emery Hall – Bromley Mission, undated, 1959-1980 (Box 1)
  - Merging of Episcopal and Government Schools, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Ministry of Education,, undated, 1963-1980 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, undated, 1930-1993 (Box 1)
  - Missions and Schools, undated, 1928-1998 (Box 1)
  - Missions and Schools - Correspondence, undated, 1950-2000 (Box 1)
  - Missions and Schools – Reports, undated, 1971-1976 (Box 1)
  - St. Andrew's School, undated, 1938-1980 (Box 1)
  - University of Liberia,, undated, 1975-2011 (Box 1)
- Episcopal Church
  - Agendas and Itineraries, 1957-1985 (Box 1)
  - Autonomy of the Episcopal Church, undated, 1974 (Box 1)
  - Bible Studyundated, 1972-1976 (Box 1)
  - The Bishop's Quarterly Reports to the Standing Committee, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Budgets and Finance, undated, 1955-1999 (Box 1)
  - Magazines and Newspapers (Box 2)
    - Magazines, undated, 1952-1996 (Box 2)
    - 'The Newark Churchman', 1970-1974 (Box 2)
    - 'New Day', 1955-1974 (Box 2)
    - Newspapers, undated, 1956-1998 (Box 2)
  - The Church Pension Fund,, undated, 1958-2005 (Box 2)
  - Church Women, undated, 1947-1983 (Box 2)
  - Clergy Lists, 1974-1977 (Box 2)
  - Conferences, undated, 1954-1995 (Box 2)
  - Contracts, undated (Box 2)
  - Correspondence
    - 1944-1969 (Box 2)
    - 1970-1975 (Box 2)
    - 1976-1979 (Box 2)
    - 1980-1989 (Box 2)
    - 1991-2003 (Box 2)
    - undated (Box 2)
  - Diocesan Conventions
    - 31st Diocesan Convention, undated, 1954 (Box 2)
    - 36th Diocesan Convention, 1959 (Box 2)
    - 42nd Diocesan Convention, 1965 (Box 2)
    - 45th Diocesan Convention, 1968 (Box 2)
    - 49th Diocesan Convention, undated, 1972 (Box 2)
    - 50th Diocesan Convention, undated, 1972 (Box 2)
    - 51st Diocesan Convention, 1974 (Box 2)
    - 52nd Diocesan Convention, undated, 1975-1977 (Box 2)
    - 53rd Diocesan Convention, undated, 1975-1976 (Box 2)
    - 54th Diocesan Convention, undated, 1976-1977 (Box 2)
    - 55th Diocesan Convention, undated, 1978 (Box 2)
    - 56th Diocesan Convention, undated, 1978-1979 (Box 2)
    - 57th Diocesan Convention, undated, 1980 (Box 3)
    - 58th Diocesan Convention, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
    - 59th Diocesan Convention, undated, 1981-1982 (Box 3)
    - 60th Diocesan Convention, undated, 1983 (Box 3)
    - 61st Diocesan Convention, 1983-1984 (Box 3)
    - 62nd Diocesan Convention, 1985 (Box 3)
    - 64th Diocesan Convention, undated, 1987 (Box 3)
    - 65th Diocesan Convention, undated, 1988 (Box 3)
    - 69th Diocesan Convention, undated, 1997 (Box 3)
    - 70th Diocesan Convention, undated, 1998 (Box 3)
    - 71st Diocesan Convention, undated, 1999 (Box 3)
    - 72nd Diocesan Convention, undated, 2000 (Box 3)
    - 73rd Diocesan Convention, undated, 2001 (Box 3)
    - 75th Diocesan Convention, 2003 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous Diocesan Convention, undated, 1955-2003 (Box 3)
  - Diocesan Press Service, undated, 1964-1973 (Box 3)
  - Episcopal Clergy Wives Association,, undated, 1976-2004 (Box 3)
  - Episcopal Youth Camp, undated, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Future of the Church in Liberia, undated (Box 3)
  - Lambeth Conference, 1978-1988 (Box 3)
  - Minutes, undated, 1968-1982 (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, undated, 1975-1977 (Box 3)
  - Newsletters and Bulletins
    - 'The Bishop's Newsletter',, undated, 1971-1981 (Box 3)
    - 'The Christian Rural Fellowship Bulletin', 1952-1956 (Box 3)
    - 'I.2.4(b)', 1987-1989 (Box 3)
    - 'Into the World',, undated, 1983-1987 (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous, undated, 1950-1999 (Box 3)
    - 'The Y's Men's Review', 1970-1973 (Box 3)
  - Pamphlets, undated, 1983 (Box 3)
  - Parochial Reports, undated, 1967-1977 (Box 3)
  - Prayers and Prayer Books, undated, 1952-2000 (Box 3)
  - Questionnaires, undated, 1975-1980 (Box 3)
  - Religious Organizations – Publications and Flyers, undated, 1954-2002 (Box 3)
  - Reports (Box 4)
    - 1948-1976 (Box 4)
    - 1977-2003 (Box 4)
    - Undated (Box 4)
    - Undated (Box 4)
  - Report of the Committee on the State of the Church, undated, 1973-1995 (Box 4)
  - Resolutions, Bylaws, and Constitutions, undated, 1958-1998 (Box 4)
  - Songs, undated (Box 4)
  - Theological Education Reports, undated, 1972-1981 (Box 4)
- Government and Politics
  - Amendments, Drafts and Articles, undated, 1969-1983 (Box 4)
  - Approved Revised Drafts of the Constitution, undated, 1984 (Box 4)
  - Constitutional Advisory Assembly
    - Agendas, undated, 1983 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 4)
    - Minutes, 1983 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous, undated, 1983 (Box 4)
    - Reports, undated, 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Executive Branch, undated, 1955-1996 (Box 4)
  - Judicial Branch, 1958-1975 (Box 4)
  - Legislative Branch, undated, 1978-1988 (Box 4)
  - Miscellaneous, undated, 1951-1986 (Box 4)
- Language and Linguistics (Box 5)
  - Episcopal Language Program, undated, 1974-1976 (Box 5)
  - General Linguistics Materials, undated, 1970-1979 (Box 5)
  - Institute for Liberian Languages – Correspondence,, undated, 1973-1983 (Box 5)
  - Institute for Liberian Languages – Miscellaneous,, undated, 1974-1995 (Box 5)
  - Institute for Liberian Languages - Reports,, undated, 1974-1981 (Box 5)
  - Linguistics Courses, undated, 1969 (Box 5)
  - Monthly Work Reports and Schedules for Language Project, 1980-1982 (Box 5)
  - Publications - Other Liberian Languages, undated, 1972-1989 (Box 5)
  - Vacation Institute for Training in Applied Linguistics, undated, 1974-1976 (Box 5)
  - Vai
    - American Bible Society,, undated, 1956-1970 (Box 5)
    - Bible Translations Materials, undated, 1967-1982 (Box 5)
    - Bible Translations, 1979-1987 (Box 5)
    - Bible Translations, undated (Box 5)
      General
      3 folders
    - Booklets, undated, 1976-1984 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1995 (Box 6)
    - Handwritten Notes, undated, 1952-2003 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous Materials, undated, 1973-2001 (Box 6)
    - Primers, undated, 1975-1979 (Box 6)
    - Reports, undated, 1975 (Box 6)
    - Teaching Materials, undated, 1974-1982 (Box 6)
    - Vai Translation Planning Committee, undated, 1994 (Box 6)
    - Vai Workshop, 1980-1982 (Box 6)
- Programs and Announcements
  - Death Notices, undated, 1982-2009 (Box 6)
  - Funeral Programs
    - 1963-1974 (Box 6)
    - 1975-1976 (Box 6)
    - 1977 (Box 6)
    - 1978-1979 (Box 6)
    - 1980 (Box 6)
    - 1981 (Box 6)
    - 1982 (Box 6)
    - 1983 (Box 7)
    - 1984 (Box 7)
    - 1985 (Box 7)
    - 1986 (Box 7)
    - 1987 (Box 7)
    - 1988 (Box 7)
    - 1989 (Box 7)
    - 1990-1994 (Box 7)
    - 1995-1999 (Box 7)
    - , undated, 2002-2010 (Box 7)
  - Grace Episcopal Churhc Programs, 1981-1987 (Box 7)
  - Liberia Official Gazette Death Announcements, 1954-2007 (Box 7)
  - Life Sketches, undated, 1954-2005 (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous Church Programs, undated, 1965-1999 (Box 7)
  - St. Thomas Episcopal Church Programs, 1971-1972 (Box 8)
  - Trinity Cathedral Programs, 1972-1994 (Box 8)
  - Wedding Programs, undated, 1975-2009 (Box 8)
- Subject Files
  - Bios and Profiles, undated (Box 8)
  - Blank Forms, undated (Box 8)
  - Booklets, undated, 1960-1980 (Box 8)
  - Calendars, undated, 1973-2000 (Box 8)
  - Conferences and Conventions, undated, 1974-1982 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence (Box 9)
    - 1944-1969 (Box 9)
    - 1970-1979 (Box 9)
    - 1980-1989 (Box 9)
    - 1990-2008 (Box 9)
    - undated (Box 9)
  - Handwritten Notes
    - 1928-1948 (Box 9)
    - 1972-1980 (Box 9)
    - 1981-1989 (Box 9)
    - 1990-1996 (Box 9)
    - 1997-1999 (Box 9)
    - 2000-2007 (Box 9)
    - undated (Box 9)
      4 folders
    - undated (Box 10)
  - Invitations, 1958-2008 (Box 10)
  - Lists of Names, undated (Box 10)
  - Mano River Women Peace Network, undated, 2001 (Box 10)
  - Maps, undated (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous, undated, 1963-1974 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous Pages, Flyers and Brochures, undated, 1970-1993 (Box 10)
  - News Clippings, undated, 1953-2000 (Box 10)
  - Newsletters and Magazines, undated, 1955-2003 (Box 10)
  - Newspapers, undated, 1973-2001 (Box 10)
  - Organizations, undated, 1957-1979 (Box 10)
  - Personal, undated, 1959-1996 (Box 10)
  - Receipts, undated, 1953-2005 (Box 10)
  - Reports, undated, 1972-1992 (Box 10)
  - Reports, undated (Box 10)
  - Typed Notes, undated, 1976-1982 (Box 10)